# **András Gémes**

shadowshell.io | github.com/gemesa | linkedin.com/gemesa | gemesa@protonmail.com

## **Summary**

Software engineer with 7 years of experience specializing in cybersecurity. <u>Hands-on experience</u> in binary analysis, reverse engineering and malware analysis (e.g., ransomware, loaders and botnets). Certified in <u>Sec+</u>, <u>CASP+/SecX</u>, <u>CEH</u>, <u>IMBT</u>, <u>PMAT</u> and <u>others</u>. Looking to apply my expertise as a reverse engineer, malware analyst or security researcher.

## Work experience

**Rust Software Engineer** @ HighTec EDV-Systeme GmbH - Budapest, Hungary

Feb 2023 - Present

- Implementing Rust and assembly tests for the HighTec Rust compiler
- Hardening the HighTec Rust toolchain binaries against reverse engineering
- Representing HighTec as a member of the LLVM security group

**Application Security Engineer** @ Knorr-Bremse - Budapest, Hungary

May 2018 – Jan 2023

- Implemented and evaluated static application security testing
- Resolved vulnerabilities discovered through fuzzing
- Developed and hardened CAN communication, memory management and RTOS software modules

### **Skills**

Languages: C, Rust, Python 3, Assembly (ARM64/AArch64, AMD64/x86-64), Bash

Reverse engineering (static): Ghidra, IDA, Binwalk, Joern, capa, YARA, DiE, llvm-readelf, llvm-objdump

Reverse engineering (dynamic): GDB, LLDB, QEMU, strace, eBPF, VirtualBox, Qiling, Frida, x64dbg, Sysinternals

Vulnerability research: checksec, AFL++, ROPgadget, ASan, MSan, TSan, UBSan

Network analysis and protocols: Wireshark, Suricata, Zeek, FakeNet-NG, INetSim, TCP, UDP, HTTP, HTTPS, DNS

Platforms and DevOps tools: Linux (Fedora, Ubuntu), Windows, Git, Docker, GitHub Actions, Jenkins

Embedded systems and protocols: STM32, ESP32, Wi-Fi, CAN, SPI, UART, I2C

### **Certifications**

CompTIA Security+, CompTIA CASP+/SecurityX, EC-Council CEH, Invoke RE IMBT, TCM Security PMAT and others.

## **Open source contributions**

- ghidra: contributing bug reports and patches to Ghidra, focusing on the BSim, Debugger and FunctionID features
- <u>rust-arm64</u>: writing a Rust book (*From Rust to assembly: ARM64 code generation patterns*)
- joern: working on improved binary analysis capabilities through Ghidra integration
- rustbininfo: submitting various improvements targeting the compiler version and dependency guesser
- <u>shadow-shell</u>: developing a cyber lab for shellcode analysis, using Assembly and C

#### Education

## **MSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

Feb 2016 – June 2018

Budapest University of Technology and Economics - Budapest, Hungary

#### **BSc in Mechatronics Engineering**

**Sept 2012 – Jan 2016** 

*University of Pannonia - Veszprém, Hungary* 

## **Continuous education**

Currently I am actively learning on TryHackMe, reading Blue Fox: Arm Assembly and managing my homelab.